Elementary School Entrance Ceremony
Was that okay?
Um...
Sure...
It's all blurry.
Rin, Kouki, stand next to each other!
Okay!
Kouki!
Say "cheese"!
I'll take a photo of you with Rin too, Daikichi.
Nah, I don't need a shot of myself.
You have to! She'll be all grown up before you know it.
You have to keep a record of it!
I see...
Daikichi, you need to smile!
Bunny Drop
I dunno about tomorrow
It's different than a sacrifice. Something's off
I don't think it's like some penalty game
So, why? I don't get it at all
I'm a little bit unsatisfied, but your presence
right now is more than just important
There's no such thing in this world
as something never-ending
Crying isn't painful, it's love's sweet drops, sweet drops!
I want to keep dreaming forever, ya know?
I want to be more kind, ya know?
As long as I'm with you, I'm happy
Girls sure are strong, ya know?
But sometimes we're weak, ya know?
Our wish is to be happy, happy, happy!
And those days will be happy, too!
Just wanna make you happy!
Again?!
Rin! How many times have I told you not to go wandering off?!
Uh-huh...
You're a big girl now, so act like it!
Don't give me an "Uh-huh"!
Daikichi, can I have this snack?
Snack?!
Well, it looks good...
Haven't you ever had cereal?
Nope.
I don't think I can finish this though...
No, I don't mind buying it...
But that's the kind of thing you have for breakfast.
It's okay to eat sweets with rice?
...How do I put this? It may look like sweets...
but you can have it as a meal.
You put milk on it...
Huh...
Why don't you have it for breakfast tomorrow?
Yeah! I will.
Are you gonna have it too, Daikichi?
Nah. It's not enough.
Put your cereal in here.
Okay!
Daikichi, you stink at that...
My fingers are too dry!
You're like Grandpa!
Oh, shut up!
Then I'll watch you do it!
Daikichi, there are cherry blossoms over here, so let's go home this way.
Sure.
They're blooming all over the place!
Because it's warm out.
Huge, isn't it?
They're in full bloom.
Since you're starting elementary school,
what do you say we plant something to commemorate it?
Commemorate?
It's kind of like a remembrance.
Every year, the two of you will get bigger.
I see...
I have my own tree, you know.
At home?
By my parents' house.
When I was born, they planted a fragrant olive tree.
For Kazumi, they planted a tea olive tree.
Is a fragrant olive tree the kind that smells good?
That's right.
I don't know about tea olive trees.
Well, the tea olive tree has some plain flowers and not much of a smell...
That's why Kazumi used to say,
"It's not fair! You get the one that smells nice!"
And then she'd tear the flowers off my olive tree.
When I offered to trade, she said "I don't want your hand-me-downs!"
Wait... It didn't leave a nice memory, so why do I want to put Rin through the same thing?
But I think you should get a pretty flower or a plant that blooms, you know?
Or at least some fruit.
I want a loquat!
A loquat?
Yeah, a loquat!
I have some loquat seeds from before.
You plant the seeds?
I can eat as many loquats as I want!
That's if they actually grow.
Actually, I was thinking of planting a tree that's about as tall as you, Rin.
I can't plant the loquat seeds?
It takes longer for a tree to grow compared to morning glories and other flowers.
It's like that expression.
"It takes three years for peaches and chestnuts to bear fruit...
...and persimmons take eight"!
You really are Grandpa's girl, aren't you?
How long for loquats?
I don't know, but what if it takes like 10 years?
I can wait.
By that time, you'll probably be more interested in fancy sweets.
I can't imagine it...
Daikichi, hurry up!
If we don't hurry, it'll be a long time before we can eat them!
Yeah, yeah...
Is this enough?
Yeah. If it's too deep, the bud won't be able to come out.
I see.
You're Grandpa's girl through and through...
I hope the bud comes up soon!
Yep...
Rin, do you know what a ninja is?
Yeah, Kouki says he's gonna be a ninja.
Ninjas jump over a hemp plant every day, while the plant gets taller and taller.
By the time the plant is full grown, they can jump incredible heights!
Really?
Why don't you try that with your loquat?
I will!
Like that.
Like that?
Uh-huh.
Hey, how tall does a loquat tree get?
About as high as our roof?
I dunno... Well...
Yeah, that's probably about right...
Okay, let's go inside.
All right. After ten more times!
I wonder if it'll sprout tomorrow...
Probably not by tomorrow...
Do you have everything?
Yep.
My teacher said someone from home has to check my schedule too.
What a pain...
They didn't do this when I was a kid.
You're right. It says "Please confirm."
Words for Communication
Fun Arithmetic
A fire?
Police car, I believe...
A crime?
I dunno.
Daikichi, attach this whistle to my bag.
Rin...
If somebody you don't know starts talking to you,
you blow on this as hard as you can.
Yeah.
And then run to the nearest house!
A store is fine, too!
All right!
Rin! School!
Daikichi! Come on, get up!
I'm gonna be late!
Okay...
Let's eat...
Let's eat!
You put milk on it.
Can I eat some of it like this?
Yeah, I guess...
Don't pet dogs eat stuff like this?
That's dog food!
It's only for dogs.
Really?
That's right!
People can't eat dog food!
Aww...
Don't be so depressed!
Is it good?
Yep. Tasty!
Rice balls are still number one though.
Those rice balls are tough to beat.
Daikichi, your phone!
Yeah...
Good morning!
I'm sorry! Kouki was so enthusiastic that he rushed out already!
Oh, that's okay.
No problem.
Okay.
Kouki's here!
He's here.
What's up?
Kouki, you've got burrs all over you!
What kind of animal trail did you run through?
I'm not an animal!
And what's with your hair?
Rin, go get a comb.
Okay!
Jeez, your schoolbag is all scratched up now...
And I bet you ran that stick across people's walls too, didn't you?
Are you a mind reader?!
It was obvious!
You did the same thing when you were little, didn't you Daikichi?
Rin, hurry up and get ready!
Okay!
What's that look for?
See you later!
Hold on a second!
You still have time...
What's wrong?!
Kouki!
You're not supposed to blow that unless something happens!
Knock it off!
Quit blowing that thing!
When you really do need help, nobody's gonna come!
Got it?
Well then, get moving.
See you later!
Watch out for cars!
Okay!
Kouki!
Let's go this way!
We're not supposed to take detours.
This isn't a detour. It's a shortcut!
I heard that ninjas...
...always take paths like these!
Sheesh...
It zigzags!
Right?
Kouki!
You're too slow!
You're making the shortcut pointless!
That's not what it's for!
Kouki...
That kid's hopeless...
I know, right?
Well, I guess it's...
Really, almost all boys are like that.
Daikichi...
The only ninja training I condone is jumping over the loquat, right?
Right!
Oh, that loquat's a school entrance remembrance, right?
Yeah.
But your olive tree is a reminder from when you were born, so it's a little different, huh?
Maybe I don't have anything like a fragrant olive tree...
You're a sharp girl...
Did that mother of hers plant a tree?
Maybe there's one at Grandpa's house.
Yeah, Grandpa might've...
But you don't know anything about one, do you?
No.
And Grandpa's gone...
If I don't know about it, no one does, right?
I never should've told her about the olive tree...
Daikichi! You've got your elbow on the table again!
Right. Sorry...
Shit...
I didn't think we'd be meeting again.
I didn't think I'd see you again either.
This is from her school entrance ceremony.
Thanks...
A tree for Rin?
There is one! There was one!
There is?!
Um... I think there was.
Why are you so iffy about it?
Because Souichi's the one who planted it...
So he did...
I'd like to move that tree to my place.
What kind of tree is it?
A small one...
No, do you know what kind?
And where...?
Mmm, it's still small...
And the branches are thin...
Should be here.
You are an artist, yes?
I'm not paid to draw maps!
Which way is north?
North?
The sun rises in the west, so...
The opposite! It rises in the east!
Never mind the directions.
Just draw the street that's in front of the house.
Oh, yeah... Duh.
Well, I've got work to do, so excuse me.
Thank you for the ice cream.
Sorry to bother you when you're so busy...
I wonder if I have my own tree...
I'm sure Grandpa planted something for you, Rin.
That's what my heart tells me.
And even if there isn't, I think you can plant another tree
to commemorate starting elementary school.
A six-year-old tree.
Yeah...
Do you want to see Daikichi's tree?
Yeah, I wanna see it!
It's big, isn't it?!
That's because it's 30 years old, just like Daikichi.
It got big, and so did he!
It's a fragrant olive tree, right?
That's right. You know your trees.
Daikichi told me.
This one's Kazumi's tree.
Tea olive?
Right...
Do you remember the big tree in Grandpa's backyard?
Oh, that one...
That's my tree, another tea olive.
Oh, really?
Huh? This tree...
Grandpa planted it when I was born.
You have the same tree as Kazumi, huh?
That's right.
When I was a child, I always compared my height to it.
I loved it, which is why I continued the tradition here.
Was that a tea olive tree?
Did Daikichi compare his height with his tree, too?
Of course!
Long before the day we first met...
Daikichi, is that...
It has the same leaves!
It's a six-year-old fragrant olive tree...
The same as mine.
This'll do.
Shoot!
What?
It's too late to jump over this one, isn't it?
I don't think even I could do it...
And we weren't even aware Rin existed until six months ago, you know?
I know...
Daikichi! The train's gonna leave!
Coming!
Well...
I'll see you off.
But...
long before the day we first met,
we were all already walking down the same path.
A sunny early Sunday afternoon
Let's go somewhere today
It's the same road I'm used to traveling
But I can see it sparkling so bright
With the sun shining down its warmth
And you here by my side...
I'm already high, high, high
I feel like dashing out
Sing, la, la, la
My voice out to forever
I'm already high, high, high
Ride the dancing wind
Sing, la, la, la
My voice springs up
Daikichi!
What's wrong?!
What happened?!
There's a strange old man outside!
Kouki...
No... That man is...
What?!
Daikichi, he's not...
Where is he?!
Enough! Both of you, listen to me!
That's our neighbor, Mr. Matsui!
Don't call him a "strange old man"!
I'm sorry...
I'm... sor...ry...
I'm the one who should apologize.
Apparently, my sudden greeting frightened him.
Sorry about that.
No, no, he was incredibly rude.
Well, be careful going to school.
See you later!
Thank you.
When you ran away, you dragged Rin along with you.
But Kouki made a mistake...
If Kouki's with you, I feel a little more reassured.
Just a little?!
Yeah, just a little!
You're still a runt!
I'm not a runt!
We're gonna be late...